[man 22] Was there a Vaccine card?
[woman 10] No. It was all for nothing.
[man 22] What do we do now?
[tense music playing]
[man 8] What's wrong?
You don't look so good.
- [man 1] I… I'm fine.
- [man 10] No lying, now.
Be honest.
Did someone turn you into a zombie?
[man 1] I… Yeah. I was infected.
- [man 10] He was trying to hide it!
- [man 1] No! I was just about to tell you.
And besides, I remember
the face of the guy who did this to me.
Then let's fucking kill him.
[gasping]
[man 8] You. You're up next.
- Go kill that zombie.
- Me?
[gasps]
No. Send someone else.
This one's practically still a kid.
It's okay. Pick someone else.
Bro, how is that fair for the people who
already had to use their Shotgun cards?
What, you think anybody here
actually wants to take a life, huh?
No one should be forced to kill anyone.
[laughs]
You think you're better than us? Hmm?
I bet you've killed someone
in a game before.
[man 8 giggles]
Surviving these games is impossible
without some sacrifice.
Go on.
[Arisu] No. Stay!
- [grunts]
- [man 2] Arisu!
- [man 3] What the hell?
- [man 8] Hold him down!
- [coughing]
- [man 3 grunts]
[man 8] Now, if you don't go,
we'll shoot this guy instead.
[man 3 coughs]
- [groaning] Don't… do it.
- [men grunting]
[Arisu] Please, Ikeno.
There's gotta be another way.
[tense music continues]
[computer over PA] Show your cards.
I'm sorry.
[gasps]
- [whirring]
- [yelps]
[gasping]
[theme music playing]
[silence]
[poignant music playing]
I'm so sorry.
[inaudible]
[sobbing]
[PA chimes]
[computer] Four rounds remain.
Please choose your opponent
and touch them.
[squeaking]
[Ikeno] You took your sweet time.
Yeah.
Did you do it?
[inhales shakily]
Yeah, it's done.
[sighs]
[suspenseful music playing]
Good job, kid. Yeah!
Clap for him. Clap!
[applause]
[Ikeno] Ah-he-hem!
Way to go!
[applause stops]
[suspenseful music continues]
[Arisu] Where's Nobu?
[woman 1] Oh, he said
he was coming right back.
[panting]
Nobu?
[man grunting]
- [man 24] Stop!
- Hey.
[man 24] Let go of me! [grunts]
[panting]
[groans]
This guy…
he turned that kid into a zombie.
[Ikeno] What kid?
- Nobu's a zombie now?
- [man 9] Yeah, that's right.
Not Nobu…
[man 10] Well, where did he go?
[man 17] I saw him!
He went off that way, alone.
[Ikeno] That son of a bitch.
Bring him back!
- [man 17] Got it!
- [man 25] Let's go!
The zombies are trying
to hide their infections.
Like Masato did. Nobu too, same thing.
Maybe there's even more zombies among us…
Yeah, you're right.
Some of you are suspicious.
[man 3 breathing shakily]
N… no. [shudders]
No! I'm not, no!
Wait, hang on! He's just…
It's symptoms of drug withdrawal.
Boss, what about the girl
who started all this? She's a zombie.
Come to think of it… where did she get to?
What if she's…
Maybe the zombies have been spying on us.
[Ikeno] What?
[man 10] Well, do we even know
if she has a Vaccine card?
What if it was all a lie?
Yeah, what if her plan was to infect
a bunch of us the whole time she was here?
Huh?
[sighs]
The game's almost over now, anyway.
I don't think we need the zombies
in order to win.
If you find a zombie in here,
just shoot 'em.
[music intensifying]
[yelps]
Sh!
[music quietens]
- [Masato gasps]
- [man 26] What are you doing?
- [man 23] What?
- [man 27] Come on, let's go.
- [man 26] They're not going to…
- [man 23 groans] No…
[sighs]
- [man 26] Let's go.
- [man 23] You're hurting me!
[grunts]
[Masato yelps]
[all yelling]
- [man 27] He's getting away!
- [man 28] Stop! Someone get him!
[panting]
[whimpering]
Hey!
Just a sec.
Uh, I need you to do me a favor.
- What favor?
- [panting]
Can… can you… use your vaccine on me?
- [man 28] He's here!
- [Masato yelps]
[wails]
- No. No, please, don't! Don't kill me!
- [man 28] Stop running!
[Masato] Don't! Get away from me!
- [wails]
- [man 28] Get up.
- [computer] Three rounds remain.
- [Masato sobbing]
Please choose your opponent
and touch them.
[whimpers]
[sighs] Fuckin' zombies.
Let's shoot them all!
- [man 28] Get up!
- [Masato yelps]
[man 28 grunts]
- [Masato whimpering]
- [man 28 grunts]
[quiet, tense music playing]
Please play your cards.
[dramatic music playing]
[Arisu] Nobu.
[music fades]
You're a zombie, aren't you?
Huh?
I can tell.
Listen.
I need you to do exactly what I say.
[quiet, suspenseful music playing]
[Rei] It's too bad, you know?
I really thought
you'd have figured it out by now.
How far the infection has
actually spread out there.
From where I'm sitting, you might be
better off as a zombie after all.
What? [scoffs]
How could you possibly know that?
Because I know that humans
are emotional creatures.
It takes a lot to shoot someone.
And those Vaccine cards are so precious.
You think they'd just
use one on a stranger?
And while the little humans
hold on to their cards,
the zombies will multiply and multiply.
And once you're infected,
there'd be no reason to hold off
on using your Zombie card to win.
When the game started,
there were four zombies.
If the infection were
to grow exponentially,
which is what
math would tell us to expect,
to go from four zombies to a majority
of the players would take
three rounds.
Isn't it obvious
which side has the advantage?
Mmm, not fallin' for that.
Why would I believe ya?
Whether you believe me or not is
completely besides the point.
Either you're gonna shoot me and I'll die,
which gives you
a couple more rounds before you're killed,
or you accept my deal now.
You become a zombie, and you survive.
[Masato breathing shakily]
[computer] Show your cards.
[whimpers]
[gasping]
[Ikeno] It's tempting.
But I'm gonna pass on your deal.
- [whirring]
- [yelps]
[gasping]
[Nobu] No.
[Arisu] Masato…
- We're too late.
- We're not gonna make it.
Rei'll be next.
- We're finished!
- Nobu.
- We're gonna die!
- Nobu!
[gasping]
Remember what I told you.
[breathing shakily]
- [music fades]
- [swallows]
[running footsteps receding]
- [man 28 sighs]
- [man 9 chuckles]
We're in charge. We're gonna win.
[woman 11] At what cost?
This has gone too far!
[man 10] The zombies want to kill us
because we killed their teammates.
But we don't have to be scared.
You know zombies don't have a way
to kill humans in this game.
Although if you do wanna die,
you can get infected any time you want.
[suspenseful music playing]
[shuddering]
Those guys are losing it.
We gotta get out of here.
[both sigh]
Nobu! Hey, Nobu!
- [Nobu gasps]
- Hurry! Stay down!
[Nobu panting]
What's going on?
[gasping] You gotta listen to me.
[wheezing]
What's wrong?
[Ikeno sighs]
Bitch tricked us.
[music fades]
Rei…
[Rei gasps]
[sighs]
You're not dead.
[PA chimes]
[computer] Two rounds remain.
- Choose your opponent and touch them.
- [man 10] We gotta find them!
[Rei] Why did you pick me to play against?
Rei, I wanna know
who you think is gonna win.
The zombies, obviously.
- And that's what you've always believed?
- Well, yeah.
Either the zombies win because they grow
exponentially, which would make sense,
or the humans become merciless killers
and execute all the zombies.
I figured it would come down
to one or the other.
- Rei.
- Arisu?
Be honest with me.
You're not a zombie, are you?
Please play your cards.
[quiet, tense music playing]
[Arisu] Let's suppose you are a zombie.
You work hard to build
this trust barricade.
And then what? What's your plan?
If nobody opts to save you
with their vaccine, that means
you'd be killed by the game.
You wouldn't rely on someone
saving you out of gratitude.
A calculating mind like yours?
No way that's a part of your plan.
You might believe in humanity,
but you don't trust it.
I see. Keep going, Arisu.
Okay… Let's assume the zombie
thing was always just an act.
Your plan makes a lot more sense.
You think I'm that smart, Arisu?
Even if you weren't a zombie at any point,
it still helps you.
Because if you build trust
with a large enough group,
if they buy into your logic,
survival is guaranteed.
So you lie,
and trust is born out of the lie.
The illusion was the key.
That's how you survived.
I see. That's a fascinating theory…
And that's also why,
when you played against Ikeno last round,
he didn't kill you.
Because he still had
his Shotgun card, right?
But because you're not a zombie,
he would not have been
able to take you out.
Show your cards.
So?
After all that,
you still didn't answer my question.
Why play against me?
I'm playing you to save you, Rei.
A zombie?
[dramatic music playing]
[sighs]
Even somebody who's that honorable
can still tell a lie.
[chuckles]
Now you're a zombie too.
But if the zombies were
always going to win,
why not become one right away?
I thought about that for a long while,
but I couldn't commit too soon.
The barricade wasn't a con. Back then,
I thought the humans had a chance.
That's why I built it in the first place.
But I couldn't really know.
My plan was to make a choice
late in the game.
But… after watching Ikeno and the others,
I started to see that ruthlessness
was just what the humans needed.
But now I see.
I know which side will win.
So thank you.
- [PA chimes]
- The final round will now begin.
[music stops]
We gotta go.
How long have you been a zombie, Arisu?
I always was.
- [tense music playing]
- [chuckles]
[door closes]
Oh, he's good.
Natsu!
- Shion!
- Arisu! [gasps]
I got infected, just like Nobu said to do.
Just one more round to make
sure we're all zombies.
Where's Nobu now?
He went to find Tetsu.
[gasping]
[groaning]
Shit! [gasping]
Tetsu!
[tense music continues]
[gasps]
Wait, please.
Just wait, hang on a sec!
- [Kazuya] Ah.
- [Nobu] Get off of me!
- [man 17] Not here.
- [man 28] What about down there?
[woman 11] No, I checked!
- Hey! He's over here!
- [man 28] Come on! Let's go!
[man 17] Go, go! Get them!
[grunts]
[man 9] Get back here!
- [grunts]
- [yelps]
- Run! We're out of time! Find Tetsu!
- Yeah! Okay!
[gasps] Tetsu!
[grunts]
[music fades]
[gasps]
Over here!
- [dramatic music playing]
- [gasps]
[man 28] That way!
- [man 30] Come on, quick! He's down there!
- [gasping]
[PA chimes]
[computer] Please choose your opponent
and touch them.
Nobu! You have to do it now!
You can't kill me without a shotgun!
Bring it on!
[roars]
[Tetsu panting]
Show your cards.
[music fades]
- [yells]
- Tetsu.
- [screaming]
- Tetsu!
- I can explain it all later.
- [sighs]
[poignant music playing]
[thumps table]
[groaning] No!
[sniffles]
It's okay, Kazuya.
This is gonna save you.
Huh?
[PA chimes]
The final round is over.
Now announcing totals.
Zombies…
Thirty-two.
Humans…
Thirteen.
- Zombies win.
- [gasps]
[players gasping and laughing]
[cheering]
[sobbing]
[woman 2] Oh, I can't believe it!
[sighs]
[players celebrating]
With only 13 people,
it is game over for the humans.
Fucking hell…
[players gasping and shouting]
- [woman 12] Yes! I can't believe it!
- [woman 13] We won!
[music fades]
You should come with us.
[emotional music playing]
PLEASE PROCEED 16 KM SOUTHWEST
THE "GAME" WILL BE HELD
AT SUNDOWN IN TWO DAYS
[music fades]
[Tetsu groans]
[sighs]
[opening zip]
You don't need to feel guilty.
I'm not feeling anything.
It's only a game.
That's right. [sighs]
[grunts]
[sighs] Let's get some sleep.
[Tetsu groans]
- [sighs]
- [Kazuya sighs]
And finished.
Doing this will help
with the morning tangles.
Thank you, big sis.
- I'm not your sis.
- [both laugh]
[Shion sighs]
Hey, look.
Isn't Arisu gonna sleep?
He's probably thinking about his wife.
[woman 2 sighing] Yeah.
I wish mine were like that.
My husband would never.
Too busy getting angry.
Too busy hitting me.
Every day, I woke up wishing he was dead.
But that sort of devotion…
it must be really nice.
- You bitch!
- [screams]
- You're worthless! Fuck you!
- No, please! Stop!
[gentle, wistful music playing]
[sighs]
[sighing]
- [Usagi] Arisu…
- [Arisu, on phone] Will I see you tonight?
[Usagi sobbing]
Hey, Usagi.
Where are you?
[Usagi breathing shakily]
Arisu…
[sobbing]
[Arisu] Hmm?
I'll come get you.
Usagi?
Please.
- Wait, hold on--
- [beep]
Dad… I'm sorry.
[Usagi] When I dream…
I can feel him.
My father's presence.
I wanna see him again.
And even if he dies in the dream…
I want to feel that pain again.
[gasping]
Daddy. Don't leave.
Dad! Please, no! Don't do it! [gasping]
Don't do it! [sobbing]
[gasps]
[Ryuji] There's something
I wanna ask you about your father.
Can you help me?
[Usagi] If my father is in my dreams…
then I need to be where I can find him.
Even in a nightmare.
[whooshing]
[deep creaking]
[rustling]
[music fades]
[sighs shakily]
[foreboding music playing]
[woman 14 gasping]
[yelps]
[woman 15 gasping]
[man 31] Hey, look out.
- [energy buzzing]
- [players yelping]
[screaming]
[energetic music playing]
[squelching]
[gasping]
[man 32 yelps]
[man 33 grunting]
[panting]
- [Ryuji grunts]
- [man 33 yells]
[man 34 yelps]
[screaming]
- [woman 16 screams]
- [man 34 yelps]
- [Usagi] Get down!
- [man 34 yells]
[music stops]
- Stop using these people as shields!
- [woman 17 screams]
You should be looking out for yourself.
[energetic music resumes]
- [Usagi gasps]
- [man 35 yells]
- [woman 18 whimpers]
- [Usagi coughs]
[Ryuji] Whoa! Move!
[woman 19 screams]
[wheezing and coughing]
- [both panting]
- [music stops]
[Usagi gasps] Come on!
- [dynamic music playing]
- [both grunting]
[Ryuji grunts]
- Ryuji, when I move, you go.
- Uh-huh.
[music fades]
[woman 15] I still can't believe
you made it through with the wheelchair.
[Ryuji] Yeah, well… I had a bit of help.
[woman 14] Usagi, are you,
like, a pro athlete?
[Usagi] Nope.
I do climb mountains as a hobby, though.
It's like I've…
met you before or something.
Hang on. Usagi's, like,
your real name, not a nickname?
- Usagi…
- [Usagi] Yep.
Your dad was
a mountain climber, too, right?
Maybe I saw your name
in a sports magazine.
Wait, no. You mean
the guy who was all over the news?
Because he killed himself
after he lied about a climb?
- [woman 15] Yeah, him.
- [both chuckle]
[woman 15] Oh…
My bad.
Those magazines are trashy.
I wouldn't worry about 'em.
- [woman 14] Hey.
- [woman 15] Trashy but true.
[woman 14] You think
the suicide thing is true too?
- [woman 15] Why don't you ask her?
- [woman 14] No way! I can't.
[woman 15] Ask her.
You don't really care
what they think, right?
My dad wasn't the kind of person
who would lie to anyone.
He wouldn't kill himself, either.
You probably have
to tell people that every day.
But, be honest, do you really believe it?
[Usagi] If it weren't for you,
I would never have come back here.
[tense music playing]
[Ryuji] Really?
It's funny. When we first met,
I felt like we were the same.
That we were both consumed
by thoughts of death.
You wanted to be with your dead father.
Right? That's what you've always wanted
more than anything.
You would never have accepted
my invitation otherwise.
You're not wrong,
but I never wanted to come back here.
[sighs]
I didn't want to make Arisu suffer.
Deep down, you don't believe that.
No. That's not who I am.
I've always wanted to come here.
To see it.
I couldn't stop thinking about it.
This in-between place linking our world
to the land of death.
[music fades]
[unsettling music playing]
[panting]
I knew you'd be the one to survive.
[breathing shakily]
Who are you?
Tell me.
Do you know who I am?
Oh yes.
I've devoted my new life
to finding people just like you.
People with the right qualities
to become capable citizens.
What do you mean?
You've played these games
many times before.
Despite your condition,
you fought your way through, and survived.
You reached your goal.
You should remember now.
I have a request for you.
There's a certain woman
I want you to bring to this place.
And in exchange, I will make sure
you see the world you desire.
Am I right that you want
to see the land of death?
For far beyond this place between worlds,
you will find death's true domain.
So what will it be?
Do you agree to my terms?
[Ryuji gasps]
If I do this,
promise me I'll get what I want.
- You will.
- How do I get her here?
This woman still carries within her heart
the shadow of her dead father.
Invite her to this place,
and she will come.
What do you mean?
How do I invite her?
[sighs]
Just have her drink this.
You do that,
and you'll get what you've always wanted.
So… are you in?
All right.
[sighs] I'll do it.
[engine thrumming]
[unsettling music continues]
[Yaba] I have to admit,
I didn't think he would agree
to bring her here.
But your plan is coming together.
And Arisu has joined as well.
Arisu won't abandon Usagi.
I've learned that human emotions are like…
invisible threads.
One only has to pull to make them move.
[Yaba] So what's your next step?
To put Ryuji to good use.
The man is quite an asset.
[Yaba] An asset, maybe, but odd too.
Who goes looking for the land of death?
He's far from normal, to be sure.
But he and Usagi are connected
in spirit now.
Those threads get pulled, and he's mine.
The game is finally getting interesting.
[laughs]
Wonderful idea.
Hmm.
[unsettling music continues]
[music stops]
[musical chiming over PA]
[computer] The required number
of teams has been reached.
The game will now begin.
THE TRAIN IS ARRIVING
[train engine humming]
[chiming]
[quiet, menacing music playing]
NOT IN SERVICE
Game, Runaway Train.
Game rules.
This train is operated without a driver.
If you can successfully move from
the starting car to the lead car,
and, after hearing the siren…
[siren blares]
…stop the train, you clear the game.
When you move to the next car,
the door will automatically lock.
And after 30 seconds,
either oxygen or poison gas
will be released.
[woman 15] Poison gas?
Excluding this starting car,
you will proceed through eight train cars.
Poison gas will be released
in four of the cars.
Upon entering a new car,
you will have 30 seconds to decide
whether to put on your mask.
Each player will receive five canisters.
Please attach the canister
to the insertion port
on the right side of your mask.
[hissing]
Inside these canisters is
a neutralizing agent for the poison gas.
You cannot use other players' canisters.
[buzzer sounds]
Additionally,
you cannot return to previous cars.
[buzzer sounds]
Please secure the canisters to your arm
and collect your gas mask.
- [players grunting]
- [PA chimes]
Game start.
Please proceed to the next car.
[bird chirping]
Why is there a bird?
The canary acts as a warning.
Just like in a coal mine.
If it dies, it's poison.
[Usagi] Okay.
[bell ringing]
Please make your choice.
[hissing]
[loud hissing]
[menacing music playing]
[players gasping]
[woman 15] What do we do?
[gasping and wheezing]
[woman 20 sobbing] Sohta…
- [Usagi] It's not poison.
- [canary chirps]
Wait. Does that mean we wasted a canister?
[Sohta] No, no. It's okay.
There are still four cars with poison.
And we still have four canisters.
[PA chiming]
[both gasp]
[players whimpering]
[panting]
[bell ringing]
Please proceed to the next car.
[thrilling music playing]
- [bell ringing]
- Please make your choice.
[canary chirping]
[music fades]
[loud breathing]
[tense music playing]
[players gasping]
[panicked gasping]
[woman 14] Oh my God!
[music stops]
[Sohta groans]
[woman 15] It was poison!
It was and we're okay!
[tense music playing]
CAR 3
[bell ringing]
Please make your choice.
So? What do we do?
[music stops]
I'm not putting it on.
[Ryuji] Why not?
Because they know we're afraid.
The game is betting
we'll use our masks early.
They probably want us
to waste all our canisters.
Then later… we get poisoned.
- I'm not gonna use it for this car.
- That's still just basically chance.
There must be a trick we're missing.
This is the third car.
We still need to get through five more.
We still have three more canisters
and three more poison gas cars.
[woman 20] What should we do?
No masks this time.
What if your brother got it wrong, though?
- Hey. What's your problem?
- You need to back the hell off.
[gas hissing]
[players gasping]
[ominous music playing]
No matter what you do,
you can't survive the gas.
[gasping]
[woman 14] It's not poison! We're okay!
- [laughing]
- [Sohta sighing]
[both sighing]
[man 36] We can make it.
[woman 15] She saved us.
[PA chimes]
[man 37] It's heading toward Asakusa!
I know that line! I'm pretty sure
it's heading west to Omotesando!
You're a train nerd?
[choking]
[all gasping]
[groaning]
[players coughing]
[whimpers]
[threatening music playing]
[music fades]
If we put our masks on
but it's not a poison car,
we won't have enough left to make it.
You. You know a lot about trains?
- Yeah.
- [Ryuji] Those people on the other train.
It looked like it took a while
for them to die.
They must be using a gas
that's heavier than air.
They'd need a massive amount
to fill up a whole train car.
- So what?
- So there'd need to be a tank for the gas.
Any car with poison would need space
to house a tank that big.
Where would it be?
No, no. I have no idea. I don't know!
Hey! We're running out of time!
What do we choose?
[man 38] What if
that other train was a trick?
What if maybe they showed us that
on purpose, to try and scare us?
Yeah, maybe.
If we use our masks now,
we might not have enough for the rest.
Wait…
I'm not sure,
but… this type of… of train car…
It probably shouldn't have a pantograph.
What's a pantograph?
The thing on the roof?
Exactly.
It's the thing that draws
electricity for the train.
Because if it has one, it really takes up…
It takes up a lot of room
on the train's roof.
This car… shouldn't have one.
So the roof would be open.
Let me get this straight.
There's space up there for a gas tank?
Yeah. Should be.
[man 38] Should be?
Are we really gonna trust this guy?
[bell ringing]
Please make your choice.
[tense, dramatic music playing]
[all breathing shakily]
- [man 39] What do we do?
- [man 40] I don't know!
[sighs]
[woman 20 whimpers]
[breathing shakily]
[music fades]
[woman 20 gasps]
[woman 20 weeping]
[loud breathing]
[woman 14 sighs]
[players trembling and sobbing]
[Ryuji gasps]
[players gasping]
[man 38 groaning]
[screaming and gasping]
[menacing music playing]
[choking and groaning]
- [man 38] Let me out!
- [whimpering]
- [groaning]
- [screams]
- I'm so sorry!
- [Sohta] Yuna! Get away! Move away!
[whimpering]
Help…
[sighs]
[bell ringing]
CAR 5
[dramatic music playing]
[canary chirping]
There are four cars left,
including this one.
We only have two oxygen canisters left,
then we're out.
And we know there are still
two cars with poison gas.
What's this one?
This particular car
would have a pantograph on the roof.
So then… there's no room for a gas tank.
[gasps]
[Sohta exhales]
[players gasping]
[canary chirps]
[music fades]
[Usagi sighs shakily]
[all sighing]
[trembling]
CAR 6
[man 37] Wait…
The luggage racks are different.
- Oh no.
- What is it?
[gasps]
I was wrong.
I got the model of the train wrong.
[woman 15] What?
Uh, I'm sorry, but it's not
the type that I thought it was.
So the… positions
of the pantographs are different.
I'm sorry! I have no idea what to do!
[Sohta scoffs]
So up to this point, it's all been luck?
- Yeah.
- You could have got us killed!
You piece of shit!
- You're supposed to be a train nerd!
- Ow!
- [Usagi] Stop it!
- [man 37 whimpering]
We're out of time.
[bell ringing]
Please make your choice.
[Sohta] Two oxygen canisters left,
and two gas cars left.
We can't afford any more mistakes.
So we just go with our gut?
[sighs]
Mmm.
[dynamic music playing]
I'm with you. I'm trusting her gut.
[woman 15] Me too.
I'm betting on Usagi.
I've got a good feeling.
Sure, let's take a chance.
In the end, it's a game of luck.
[exhales]
[Yuna whimpering]
Be poison gas.
Be poison gas. Be poison gas.
Be poison gas. Be poison gas!
[breathing slowly and deeply]
[music fades]
[canary chirping]
It's alive.
This isn't poison!
[ominous music playing]
[breathing shakily]
[music stops]
[theme music playing]